Yeah, you want to work here, you got to
have a felony, a tattoo, or an excuse. I
have never opened up one of these boxes.
I have never replaced one of these in my
life. We're all about to learn together.
This is kind of like Space Jams meets
Joe Durk. Joe Fails, licensed
electrician, builder, general
entrepreneur, and solar science idiot.
Julian Brown, founder of Nature Jab,
turning plastic into fuel, serial
entrepreneur, independence activist.
Adrien Hover, former football player at
the University of Alabama and the Green
Bay Packers. I'm a mechanical innovator
by nature. Serge Cortez Serge aka Prof,
the master of the code here to train how
to be the best in the trades. Nutrition.
Here we go. We going to face a solar
generator. Has anybody ever seen inside
a solar generator? No. This is a battery
Evo Walwish Gen 3 solar generator. 22
kWh battery bank. 12 1/2 KVA inverter.
Split phase 120 and 240 output. You can
plug solar right into it. here. Charge
it off the grid right here. It's all in
one. To turn it on, you just hit a
button. I've put 2422 kwatt hours
through this one box. The issue we're
having is this. I should say never
disconnect a live solar circuit, but
it's a little late for all that.
Whenever you're messing with a solar
generator, you have to know what you're
working with. You got to read the book.
Solar input, 80 amps. PV input. The
machine will charge between 90 and 230
volts. 209 cooking. Yep. All right.
Should the machine work? Yes, it should
because it only needs a minimum of 90.
Nothing.
Nothing. All right. So, it can't take
power in. Let's confirm that it's a
working circuit.
Orange light. It's charging. Getting 230
right there. So, we know there's a
problem here with the charger. It's
getting output. It's not getting input.
We know we're not have a problem with
our output. I can tell you it's this.
This is the part that's bad. What I love
about battery evo [__] is it's all
modular. You can just take out some
screws and replace it. It's turned off,
right? Yeah. Wait a minute.
Still running. You got to turn it off.
Battery has a switch. You could
disconnect this one.
But this one would still be connected.
There we go. Now it's off. Just two
screws. That was simpler than I thought.
I can see it right now. Yep. Terminals.
That's it. Yep. The terminal. So, let's
look. Can we find the PV input? You can
see the PV charger right here. Right.
The wires are going right here.
Well, looks about the same. Tons of room
to work in here. Let's see what we're
looking at in here. Let's see if I can
maestro for y'all a little bit cuz I've
never seen this. I see my 240 output.
Okay. So, if that's going in here, we're
going to follow these wires up here. Oh,
what is this, Serge? What does this look
like to you? That's our tremolo right
there. Oh, that looks like a bus bar
sometimes. Bus bar for sure. Red to red,
black to black, white to white. Okay, so
if that's our terminal, these are our
outputs. Look, I see some going over
here to my 120. I see some going over
here to my 240. I know that's my
terminal. So, if that's my terminal,
what must this be?
What are these? I don't know what this
is. Look at this. It's going down to
these coils. Look at the coil. Oh shoot.
That that now that has to be the
inverter. That's the inverter cord.
Surely
this must be some type of control. Yeah,
controller. If we had to take all this
out. Look. Screws. Look, everything has
four screws in it. Beautiful. Wow. Ship
me apart instead of me shipping this
back. I love it. What do we got to do to
take it out? Notice all of these are red
guarded in so they don't come out when
you ship it. Oh, they sure are. Mhm.
Correct purpose.
There you get this guy out.
Need a flathead. Hey, let me get this
thing out where I can work on a little
more. How about that? I need to remember
where they're hooking back up, too.
Well, if you if you just take off this
right here. But look, black to black
right here. Oh, yeah. So, which
terminals do they go on? Hey, why don't
we take some pictures? Yep. Smart. I
should have done that to begin with. I
always do that because a phone remembers
better than I do. It's a digital memory.
That's on that one. Okay. And then now
what else? All right. No, then we have a
fan switch right here. Get a picture of
this fan switch. This one. We do have a
screw that's under this bus bar. Oh, I
see it. Well, that screw is already
stripped the [__] out. Look. But that's
it. And then we could take it the whole
thing out without having to do the It's
like working on a car. You might have to
move this. Yeah. You would try to avoid
it if you could just one screw. That'd
be That'd be awesome. Yeah. Oh, see it
perfect. Look at that. Look at that. We
got one on the back. Probably got it.
Gucci. Yep. Hey, a blend of of of
intelligence and trade knowledge. Now we
have two screws that are stripped out.
How do we get them out, Serge? Oh, I see
that. Oh, yeah. Now we either one. You
got a a good special B screwdriver. Aha.
Fire. Fire. Got to tilt the right way.
There we go. Now we get some leverage.
Now you get some leverage. Little force.
This is what you're talking about. I'll
cut the [__] off with a sawzaw. I got
you.
Nope. All right. Okay. Hold on. That
[__] is red guarded down, too. But they
do this. Why do they do this? Why do
they red guard it? Keep that torque.
Hey, Serge. What causes causes a fire?
Loose connections. Boom. Loose. Oh,
yeah. Okay. Imagine you shipped a solar
generator across the country from
California to Georgia. You want to get
loose, right? What do you think would
happen if it did? A fire. Hey, but look
what they have in here in case not. You
see what this is? Is that a fire
extinguisher? That is a fire
extinguisher. Good built-in fire
extinguisher. I used these when my van
caught on fire from a fuel leak in New
Mexico. I had those in there and that's
what saved my van. I [__] you not. I
have the ones I used. Uh-huh. Crazy.
Which way you pushing? I'm going to go
turn it. I'm going to go that way.
Counterclockwise. Okay. All right. Bet.
Ready? Yes. Steady. Go.
Hey,
come on, baby.
[__] We ain't good. We good at it.
[__] Hey, these screws is [__]
Made it work, though. Hey, don't go back
in. Now look, now let's compare. You
see? Well, there's the Look at the
difference in the coils. Oh yeah. Night
and day. Let's see where they burn up.
Alex said they smelled it. They smelled
it burning. And you know it smell too.
Also, let's see. Look at the difference.
They've upgraded some things. Yep. Look
at that white [__] between that board. I
bet you that has a lot to do with it.
What they're connecting. You see that
circuit board now? It has some more
insulating something to pass through.
Yeah. I don't know what that is, but
it's added. And they got these a little
further apart. These are different
colors. These capacitors. Look how this
is taller. See that? Yep. All these have
that white [__] on them. Upgraded. Now,
let's put it back. You got to be doing
something right or something really
wrong to get here.
All of the above.
All right. So, boom. Boom. Bingo. Bongo.
Now we have battery back in.
Yep. Machine a little bit. Let's make
get that lined up there. God bless the
man that invented the battery. I mean,
the magnet bit. Yeah. No, seriously. I
know that whoever invented the flathead
screwdriver, the biffold door, and the
popcorn texture, that's all the same
family.
I hate all them guys. Every last one of
them. They're all inbred. I can't I
can't stand them guys. All from Alabama,
right? Now they invented something.
I made my peace with Alabama.
How did we beat him? I guess we can be
friends. I know Adrien Hubard never felt
the sting of loss when he played George
all them fabulous years. Know what it's
like to win for three quarters. Adrian.
So, look, I'm going to guess on this cuz
I think I already Three pin. Three pin.
Two pins. A two pin. Where's the two
pin? Is it this? No. Where is this? No,
that you know. Let's see. Let's see. Cuz
there there was another little white. We
got a photo. He just got that one. Okay.
You think Hey, you think it's this wire
that's under here? It might be under
here. We might have. Well, look. But
this is that wire. Look. When I tug on
that, it's pulling this back. Go. Let's
see
that.
Got jammed on. Yep. Yeah. Got stuckers.
That is for the fan. What do you think
would happen if you didn't plug the fan
in? Maybe go boom. It'll take you out.
It's going to get hot. Boom.
Boom. There you go.
Those have to go over here. But which
one went where? We didn't take that
picture, did we? Well, let's see. I
think the pixel were there. It's
possible.
Yeah, but where did they go? Oh, which
orientation? Well, look at the go. Let's
scroll back to other pictures. We might
find them in the background. But let's
look at this picture. My thumb was here
and they're turned this way. So, they
had to be like this. That's my left
hand. And you see there, it's this side.
It's not that side, right? And see right
there, that's your connection point.
Yeah. Do we agree? We agree. Looks like
the red one. Yeah, the red one was under
there, but I don't see the little the
small red one either. I think those came
off of this. Ah.
Hey. Hey. Haha. Oh, then we have to
shoot. Oh, wait, wait, wait. Well, look.
Where does it plug in, too?
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yep. So, where did this
guy go? It has to go right there. That's
a two pin. And this is a two That's a
three pin there. But there's a two pin.
The two pin right there. No. Hey, but
this was on That's not the right That's
not the right. This was on the this
board, right? So, where did it come off
from? This board when you took it off of
here. It came off of this, right? So,
where did it come off?
Trixie Trixie.
Cuz they changed a few things. You see,
this has a plus and a minus. Why the
[__] won't it go on there? H.
Yes, it's Julian. Nature Jab. Plastic in
the fuel and a million. It's hitting.
Can't get it on. Okay, I'm going to
figure out where that one was. We're
going to look at these pictures. I do.
It was k. You see how it's kicked to the
side a little bit with this connector on
there? Watch. It won't go on.
Interesting. Because it was kicked to
the side. But then look, I can put that
on there and pull it back this way.
Right. Might be hitting on that glob of
red guard. Yeah. Come on.
Hot damn. All right. Alas. Ha. That was
it. That was it. Well, now we got to
screw these all together. All the
terminals. I'll hold it in there. You
screw. I don't want to strip none of
them guys out. Yeah. Get them both in
there.
Just get it. There you go. Hold on. Get
it started. Let me get a hold of this.
Mhm.
As an electrician, you know that
screwdriver is a lot better than that
drill. Oh, you definitely definitely
always. Do you wrap your outlets or stab
them? No, I wrap them. I know. That's
the worst connection to do. The worst
way. And it's the manufacturer
recommended one. Yeah, older houses.
That's what happens when uh when three
rooms go off. Like what happened?
There's a bad and then what we were just
saying, the loose connection. A loose
connection is the most dangerous thing
in a house. Most dangerous. Exactly.
Planned obsolescence.
They don't worry about the liability cuz
it's going to be way past that time.
Yep. But it will happen. It's win. All
right. Don't jab the wires in the back
of the outlet. That's the worst kind of
to do. All right. Now,
now guess what we get to do? Turn it on.
Plug it in. You see? Kaboom. Boom. All
right. So, now repeat our steps. Battery
on.
Bing.
Hey, it turned back on. That's always a
good sign. Oh, yeah. There we go. There
we go. Did you? Yes.
[Music]
Don't you love my solar confabulation?
Yes, I do. Hey, bro. Nobody ever break
in here. Nobody ever know what to do
with this. They'd be terrified. As an
electrician, this looks terrifying. Yes.
Yes, it does. But absolutely safe. I'm
telling you. Be terribly scared of me.
We got this. We got this. Perfectly
safe. Absolutely. Serge, hold this for
them so they can see. Let's check our
voltage.
206. 206.
Should the machine now work? It should
charge. Uh, let's see. No. Go. Look,
everybody's backing up. Boom. Boom.
Did
it click? I heard a click. I heard a
click. It clicked. I think I heard a
click. It clicks. I think I heard
another click.
Oh,
did you see that? Yes, I did. Okay, give
it a second to Oh, PV power. Yep. Mhm.
Fixed. Give it a second. It's thinking.
Come on.
Come on. This thing hadn't even woke up
yet. Oh,00 watts going in. It had to
restart. Now, one other thing I learned.
Look at our PV total. It has reset.
Okay. Yep. Well, guys, look. 2,000 watts
going in. 2100 watts. Sure. 42 amps
right now. That's a beautiful thing.
First try. And what time is it? 7 7
7:00. 2500 watts. Wow. Watch it climb.
Let it go. 2300.
That's energy, baby. Yes.